State University Construction Fund; Records apap097
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University Construction Fund Records
1961-1979
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
New York State University Construction Fund.
apap097
0.88 cubic ft.
A public benefit corporation formed to plan, design, construct and provide financing for facilities required by the SUNY system.
Historical Note
In 1962, the State University Construction Fund was established by the Governor and the Legislature of New York as a public benefit corporation within the State University to plan, design, construct and provide financing for facilities required by the State University of New York to meet academic program and enrollment needs. As a result of the creation of the fund and in response to an urgent need to make higher education opportunities available to additional thousands of New Yorkers, the largest university building program in history was launched in New York State. (The State University Construction Fund, Annual Report 1979, (New York: New York State University Fund, 1980).)
Scope and Contents
The collection contains campus plans for the State University of New York (SUNY) System construction in the 1960s and 1970s. Progress reports and charts in each report include the dates that architects, sketches and locations for construction were approved. The charts also provide the dates construction began for each campus in the SUNY System. The collection includes annual reports from 1964 through 1979. These provide the budget for construction and the yearly progress for each facility. The annual report for the year 1972 celebrates the first ten years of the State University Construction Fund and includes helpful retrospective information. A review of the capital program for all state universities from 1975 to 1976 and 1976 to 1977 is included in the collection and reviews of the Albany campus are available from 1971 through 1975. The article Billion Dollar Client published in the July/ August 1968 issue of Architectural Forum is also included in the collection and discusses New York's major construction project and its progress. The majority of the collection is booklets published annually to demonstrate the Construction Fund's progress. The collection consists entirely of published material.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into 2 small file series.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Campus planning -- New York (State).; College facilities -- New York (State) -- Planning.; Public universities and colleges -- New York (State) -- Buildings -- Finance -- Statistics -- Periodicals.; Reports; Politics and Politicians; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Architecture; Conservation and the Environment; Education; State University of New York -- Buildings -- Periodicals.; New York State University Construction Fund -- Periodicals.
- Reports, 1964-1979; 1
  Arrangement
  arranged chronologically
  Scope and Contents
  The Annual Reports of the State University Construction Fund generally include a summary of significant accomplishments and projects, major awards won by the individual SUNY campuses for design and construction, highlights from individual campuses including illustrations, and financial statements. The financial statements are arranged by campus or project and include the contract holder, estimated cost, and cost paid annually. These tables are available for planning and design agreements, construction underway, and construction completed. This series also includes the Campus Plan (1966), an architectural article summarizing the State University construction endeavor, and Architectural Accessibility for the Disabled of College Campuses a publication of the State University Construction Fund.
  - Campus Plans for State University of New York, 1966 (Box 1 (1-Reports), Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1964-1967 (Box 1 (1-Reports), Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Reports), Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, 1972-1974 (Box 1 (1-Reports), Folder 4)
  - Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (1-Reports), Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1975-1977 (Box 1 (1-Reports), Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (1-Reports), Folder 3)
  - Billion Dollar Client: A Progress Report on New Yorks Unique State University Construction Fund, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Reports), Folder 4)
  - Architectural Accessibility for the Disabled of College Campuses, Published by the State University Construction Fund, 1976 (Box 1 (1-Reports), Folder 12)
- Capital Construction and Campaign, 1961-1977; 2
  The series is composed of capital construction and capital campaign reports published by the State University Construction Fund. These reports are generally tabular data of construction fund building project expenses in greater detail than that provided in the annual reports of the State University Construction Fund. The capital construction reports summarize the progress of construction projects on all SUNY campuses, while the capital campaign materials cover only the Albany campus.
  - Capital Construction Progress Report, 1961 (Box 1 (2-Capital Construction and Campaign), Folder 5)
  - Capital Construction Program, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (2-Capital Construction and Campaign), Folder 5)
  - Capital Construction Program, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (2-Capital Construction and Campaign), Folder 6)
  - Review of the Capital Campaign for Albany, 1971 (Box 1 (2-Capital Construction and Campaign), Folder 7)
  - Review of the Capital Campaign for Albany, 1972 (Box 1 (2-Capital Construction and Campaign), Folder 8)
  - Review of the Capital Campaign for Albany, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Capital Construction and Campaign), Folder 9)
  - Review of the Capital Campaign for Albany, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Capital Construction and Campaign), Folder 10)
  - Review of the Capital Campaign for Albany, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Capital Construction and Campaign), Folder 11)